Register of the Costa Rican Subject Collection, 1929-1993.
Hoover Institution Archives
Costa Rican Subject Collection,
1929-1993
XX804
2 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (2.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Costa Rica--Politics and government.; Elections--Costa Rica.; Nicaragua--History--1979-1990.; Hull, John, 1920-; Central America.; Civil rights--Central America.; United States--Foreign relations.; Nicaragua.; Costa Rica.
Series Description
- Subject File, 1968-1993. (Box No. 1-2.)
  Reports, serial issues,articles, pamphlets, leaflets, flyers, bumper stickers, sample ballots, campaign biographies, voter's guide and election code. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
- Oversize File, 1929-1990. (Box No. 3.)
  Posters, manifesto, sample ballots, election literature and promotional items.
Container List
See card catalog for increments that may have been received after December 1994.
- SUBJECT FILE, 1968-1993
  - General. Serial issues, pamphlets, leaflets, flyers, bumper stickers, sample ballot, campaign biographies and reports, largely concerning political parties and campaigns, 1968-1986. Includes material from the Partido Comunista de Costa Rica, Partido Socialista Costarricense, Partido Vanguardia Popular, Movimiento Revolucionario del Pueblo and student movements (Box 1., Folder 1-3)
  - Central America. Reports and pamphlets relating to Costa Rica's role in the Central American peace process, arms trafficking and the political situation in Nicaragua. Includes documentary material concerning various peace plans, including that of the Contadora group (Box 2., Folder 1)
  - Elections, 1990. Voter's guide, election code, sample ballot, bumper sticker, flyers, pamphlets and leaflets, 1989-1990 (Folder 2)
  - Human rights. Reports and pamphlet, 1987-1989 (Folder 3)
  - Trade unions. Newspaper, report and pamphlets concerning labor organizations and strike activities, 1979-1986. Includes material from the Asociacion Nacional de Empleados Publicos (ANEP) and the Confederacion Unitaria de Trabajadores (CUT) (Folder 4)
  - United States. Articles and reports mainly concerning the activities of John Hull within Costa Rica in support of the Nicaraguan Contras, 1988-1993. Includes material on the controversy surrounding allegations made against Hull and the Central Intelligence Agency by the Christic Institute (Folder 5)
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1929-1990.
  - Posters, manifesto, sample ballots, election literature and promotional items. Includes material from La Liga Antifascista de Costa Rica and the Partido Socialista Costarricense (Box 3.)